Milly sat under the apple tree and watched the [rain clouds] sweep over [the hills].
-- 米莉坐在蘋果樹下，看著[雨雲]掠過[山丘]。
What a [wet] day!
-- 多麼[潮濕]的一天！
She ate an apple and waited for the rain to stop.
-- 她吃了一個蘋果，等著雨停。
Soon it did.
-- 很快就成功了。
The sky [turned blue] again, and the Sun [shone], warm and golden.
-- 天空又[變藍]了，太陽[照耀]著，溫暖而金色。
Then she saw the rainbow.
-- 然後她看到了彩虹。
It began as an [explosion] of light, high in the clouds.
-- 它開始時，就像光線在高處雲層[爆炸]。
The sky filled with [dazzling colors]: blue, orange, green and purple.
-- 天空充滿了[耀眼的色彩]：藍色、橙色、綠色和紫色。
Then both ends of the rainbow began to fall to Earth...
-- 然後彩虹的兩端開始落到地球上……
The rainbow landed in the garden.
-- 彩虹降落在花園裡。
‘Wow!’ Milly went closer and touched the rainbow.
-- “哇！”米莉走近，摸了摸彩虹。
She felt nothing, just air.
-- 她什麼都感覺不到，只有空氣。
But the colors moved [beneath] her fingers.
-- 但是顏色在她的手指[下]移動。
When she looked up, the rainbow seemed to be [stretching] on and on into space.
-- 當她抬頭看時，彩虹似乎一直[延伸]到太空中。
'What would happen if I [stepped inside] it?' she wondered.
-- “如果我[走進去]會發生什麼？” 她想知道。
There was only one way to find out...
-- 只有一種方法可以查明...
She stepped inside.
-- 她走進去。
It was beautiful!
-- 它過去挺美！
And very quiet.
-- 而且很安靜。
Milly couldn’t hear anything.
-- 米莉什麼也聽不見。
She [looked up].
-- 她[抬起頭]。
The rainbow seemed to go on forever...
-- 彩虹似乎永遠持續下去……
WHOOSH! Milly was [sucked up] by the rainbow.
-- 嗖！ 米莉被彩虹[吸了上去]。
It was a [tunnel] of light.
-- 那是一條光之[隧道]。
She [whizzed along] like a button up a [vacuum cleaner].
-- 她像按下[吸塵器]上的按鈕後一樣，[呼嘯而過]。
Wind [whistled past] her ears.
-- 風從她耳邊[呼嘯而過]。
She [tumbled] over and over but didn’t hurt herself: she was carried on a [soft cushion] of air.
-- 她一遍又一遍地[翻滾]，但沒有傷到自己：她被一個[柔軟的氣墊]支撐著。
Up and up and up she went, so fast.
-- 她走得越來越快，越來越快。
But rainbows go up...
-- 但彩虹升起...
and rainbows come down.
-- 彩虹降臨。
Soon she was falling down the far side of the rainbow.
-- 很快她就從彩虹的另一邊掉下來了。
She could see green below.
-- 她可以看到下面的綠色。
Green grass, rushing up to meet her, faster and faster...
-- 綠草，迎面撲來，越來越快……
BUMP! She landed hard, but nothing was broken.
-- 撞！ 她重重地落地，但沒有損壞任何東西。
Milly stood up.
-- 米莉站了起來。
She was on the other side of the valley, standing on a [steep] green hill.
-- 她在山谷的另一邊，站在[陡峭的]青山上。
She could see her house, far away.
-- 她可以看到她的房子，很遠。
It was like a tiny white box with a rainbow in the garden.
-- 它就像一個白色的小盒子，花園裡有彩虹。
Everything was [calm and peaceful] and very lovely...
-- 一切都[平靜祥和]，非常可愛……
WHOOSH! Suddenly she was shooting back through the rainbow, faster than a firework.
-- 嗖！ 突然間，她從彩虹中被射了回來，比煙火還快。
Red, blue, yellow ... stripes of light, flashing by.
-- 紅、藍、黃……一道道光紋，一閃而過。
Up, up, up she went and down, down, down...
-- 她往上，往上，往上，往下，往下，往下……
BUMP. She landed back in her own garden.
-- 碰。 她回到了自己的花園。
'Oww...!’ Milly [groaned].
-- “哇……！”米莉[呻吟]道。
‘I am going to be so [bruised] tomorrow.'
-- “我明天會[瘀青]。”
Then she had a thought...
-- 然後她有了一個想法……
'GOLD! There is always gold at the end of a rainbow!'
-- '金子！ 彩虹盡頭總有黃金！
She dropped to her knees and started to [dig].
-- 她跪下來開始[挖]。
The earth flew out behind her, covering the grass with stones and soil.
-- 泥土在她身後飛出，草地上佈滿了用石頭和泥土。
'Come on, come on! It must be here somewhere...'
-- '好啦好啦！ 它一定在這兒的某個地方……”
She went deeper and deeper.
-- 她越挖越深。
Then she saw something [shiny], under her fingertips.
-- 然後她看到指尖下有什麼[閃閃發亮]的東西。
She pulled it out.
-- 她把它拉了出來。
'Gold...'
-- '金子...'
Milly [stared at] it, [breathless with excitement].
-- 米莉[盯]著它，[興奮得喘不過氣來]。
It was a [golden coin], bigger than usual money and much heavier.
-- 那是一枚[金幣]，比平常的錢要大，也重得多。
She [rubbed it clean].
-- 她[把它擦乾淨]。
There were words written on it: [Make a wish] before the rainbow [fades].
-- 上面寫著：在彩虹[消失]之前[許個願]。
'Oh wow!' she said. 'This is [amazing]! A wish!'
-- “哦哇！” 她說。 '這真太[了不起]了！ 一個心願！'
Her head began to fill with ideas, everything she could wish for.
-- 她的腦子裡開始充滿了想法，她所希望的一切。
But then she saw something.
-- 但隨後她看到了什麼。
The rainbow was starting to fade.
-- 彩虹開始褪色。
It was going thin at the edges.
-- 它的邊緣變薄了。
'No! I haven't made up my mind! Please - wait!'
-- '不！ 我還沒想好！ 請稍等！'
But the rainbow didn't wait.
-- 但是彩虹沒有等。
It was fading. Going away, and taking her wish with it.
-- 它正在褪色。 離開，並帶著她的願望。
'No! I’ll make my wish soon. Just a moment, please!'
-- '不！ 我很快就會許願完成。 請稍等片刻！'
But still the rainbow was fading.
-- 但彩虹仍在消退。
The golden coin was getting hot in her hand.
-- 金幣在她手中越來越燙。
'Ohh....! Choose... choose... Yes. YES! I have it!'
-- 啊……！ 選擇……選擇……是的。 是的！ 我有它！
Milly closed her eyes and made her wish and VOOMF!
-- 米莉閉上眼睛許下了她的願望，VOOMF！
The rainbow disappeared, and so did the golden coin.
-- 彩虹消失了，金幣也消失了。
Milly hardly dared to move.
-- 米莉幾乎不敢動彈。
Had her wish come true?
-- 她的願望實現了嗎？
Maybe.
-- 或許。
She looked up.
-- 她抬起頭。
The sky was peacock blue.
-- 天空是孔雀藍。
The Sun was golden, warm on her face.
-- 陽光是金色的，溫暖地照在她的臉上。
Such a beautiful day.
-- 多麼美好的一天。
Such a beautiful world.
-- 如此美麗的世界。
'Even if the wish doesn't come true, I am a very lucky girl,' she said.
-- “即使願望沒有實現，我也是一個非常幸運的女孩，”她說。
And she smiled.
-- 她笑了。
--